Now, let's talk a little more deeply about synchronous versus asynchronous JavaScript.
让我们比较一下同步和异步 JavaScript
JavaScript naturally is a single-threaded programming language,
JavaScript 是一门单线程语言
which means for the most part it will be run as a single process in
大多数情况下在同一个进程中运行
your computer essentially writing and running it from top to bottom.
代码按照书写顺序 自上而下执行
So if we look at the synchronous side over here,
在屏幕左边是同步代码
we see that we have a function in which we'll
我们定义 sync 函数 在函数中调用
console.log the string first and then we call that function,
console.log("first") 然后调用该函数
and then we console.log a string second.
最后调用 console.log("second")
Because we call sync first,
由于先调用 sync 函数
we'll first see first,
因此先打印出字符串 first
and then because console.log second comes second,
然后调用 console.log("second")
and JavaScript is a single-threaded programming language it will go ahead and do second.
由于 JavaScript 是一门单线程语言 因此按顺序打印出 second
Now, this is great for many things,
处理很多问题这就够了
but what it doesn't allow you to do is it doesn't allow you to say, "Hey,
但是你无法让
JavaScript, stop for a second while you're doing
JavaScript 暂停一会儿
this and wait until something else happens."
等待另一件事情完成后再接着运行
Because sometimes we're dependent on other parts of our code.
有时候的确会碰到这种情况
So JavaScript already has had some a synchronicity built into it.
因此 JavaScript 内置了一些异步编程工具
One example, is the setTimeout function.
比如 setTimeout 函数
SetTimeout is a function that allows you to delay a function.
setTimeout 可以延迟一段时间
Here, we see it's 3,000 milliseconds.
比如 3000 毫秒后再去执行一个函数
Let's take a look at these in action to really understand how they work differently.
让我们通过一个例子理解它是怎么工作的
So first, let's try running it synchronously as we would expect.
首先看看同步执行时会如何
We go to our browser and we see instantly first comes first because it's on line sixth,
打开浏览器会看到先打印出 first
and then second comes next,
然后打印出 second
seems to make sense, it goes in order.
一点儿也不意外 因为它们是按顺序执行的
But now, let's add the setTimeout function.
现在 让我们在代码顶部
We're going to put it at the top of our code,
添加 setTimeout 函数
which means if it were running synchronously we would expect to see third, first, second.
如果代码是同步运行的 那么我们就会按顺序看到 third first second
But because it's asynchronous,
但是代码是异步执行的
let's see what happens.
因此我们会看到
The third came last,
third 是在 first second 之后 最后才打印出来的
and you saw it came after the first and second. Let's see it again.
再看一遍
First, second, and then third comes.
first second third
This is an example of a synchronicity even
这就是一个异步代码的例子
though the console.log third is at the top of our code,
虽然 console.log("third") 在代码顶端
it's put onto, you could call it a stack.
但是仿佛被推入其他什么地方
It's put away and it's being dealt with somewhere else
你可以叫这个地方为栈
while JavaScript comes through and finishes the rest of these.
当 JavaScript 执行完其他代码
Then when it's done,
无事可做时
we see it come off the stack and go right into our log.
这段代码从栈中弹出 执行并打印消息
Now, the real amazing part about a sync promises if that instead of just a time,
异步 promises 的强大之处在于 不仅可以延迟一段时间
like 3,000, we can set up condition.
比如 3000 毫秒 还可以设置条件
So we can say, we don't want the next part of
当条件满足后
this code to execute until a condition is set.
再执行这段代码
This becomes a very very powerful possibility.
这就为编程提供了无限可能